# Lewis Guignard

lewisquignard@gmail.com | 980.875.8786 | LinkedIn

# SKILLS

## **GENERAL**

Leadership / Development
Estimation / Inference
Training / Presentations
Micro-service Architectures / DevOps
Test Driven / Agile Development
Technical Sales

## PROGRAMMING / DEVOPS

Proficient:

- Python MySal
- •Amazon AWS Linux (debian/bash/zsh)
- hjkl git gitlab jira Competent:
- R .html/.css/.js Matlab  $\mbox{ET}_{\mbox{\ensuremath{\text{ET}}}\mbox{\ensuremath{\text{EX}}}\mbox{\ensuremath{\text{\bullet}}}\mbox{\ensuremath{\text{Java}}\mbox{\ensuremath{\text{\bullet}}}}\mbox{\ensuremath{\text{C}}\mbox{\ensuremath{\text{++}}}}$

# **EDUCATION**

### STANFORD UNIVERSITY

MS ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

Signal Processing, Data Science June 2016 | Stanford, CA Cum. GPA: 3.7

#### **NCSU**

NORTH CAROLINA STATE UNIVERSITY BS PHYSICS 2008-2011 | Raleigh, NC Cum. GPA: 4.0 Valedictorian

# **COURSEWORK**

## **GRADUATE**

Machine Learning Convex Optimization Signal Processing Fourier Analysis Linear Algebra

#### **UNDERGRADUATE**

Solid State Physics Modeling / Simulation

# INTERESTS

3D Printing | Raspberry Pi | Radio (KM4JQU) | Visualization | Cycling | Photography | Backpacking | T4R

# SUMMARY

A highly organized, creative data science leader with over 6 years of experience building high impact data science teams. Adept at making complex ideas intuitive and understandable. Proficiency in full data science pipeline: researching and purchasing purchasing data sources, ETL, model creation and validation, managing and deploying a stable production code-base, delivering insights to leadership team, client base and industry. Excels in developing and integrating teams of varying experience and interests.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## CYBERCUBE SNR. MANAGER, DATA SCIENCE

Jan 2020 - Current | SF, CA

Build and mature the data science team and as well as its roles and responsibilities • Expand and evangelize data science usage within the company, to engineering, GTM, sales, leadership. • Manage estimation projects • Represent analytics side of company to the industry

### CORAX CYBER HEAD OF DATA SCIENCE

Mar 2016 - Jan 2020 | SF, CA

Risk modeling for frequency and severity of cyber breach and business interruption events • Lead a team of data scientists • Manage estimation projects • Technical sales and speaking • Seek out, negotiate, and ingest new data-sources • Manage 100M daily record ingestion and analysis

#### UNDERWRITERS LABORATORIES ENGINEER

Oct 2011 - Aug 2014 | Durham, NC

Critiqued and built test plans for LED Luminaires, modules and power supplies for compliance to relevant UL or IEC international standards.

## HELMHOLTZ ZENTRUM BERLIN VISITING SCIENTIST

Jun 2011 - Sep 2011 | Berlin, Germany

Experiments in photo-electrochemical systems, semiconductor-electrolyte interfaces and nanoemitters.

# PATENTS | PUBLICATIONS | AWARDS

- Patents: US20180069889A1 US20180124092A1
- B. A. Collins, E. Gann, X. He, L. Guignard, C. R. McNeill, H. Ade. Molecular Miscibility of Polymer Fullerene Blends. The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters 0, 3160-3166
- Speaker: American Physical Society Meeting 2010 / Net Diligence Santa Monica, CA 2018 / Catastrophe Risk London 2019 / Foresight 2020

## RESEARCH

### NORTH CAROLINA STATE UNIVERSITY | RESEARCHER

Oct 2008 - Jun 2011 Raleigh, NC

Investigated organic photo-voltaic system dynamics, focusing on efficiency, morphology, material properties.